如果我把整罐橄榄吃光  你给我多少钱
How much you give me to eat this whole jar of olives?
我一分钱也不给  但你欠我两块九毛五
I won't give you anything, but you'll owe me $2.95.
成交
Done.
我需要地图  我需要地图
I need an atlas! I need an atlas!
干嘛  你要交报告吗
Why? Do you have a report due?
我要和一个外交官约会
I have a date with this diplomat I met...
我在联合国大楼外做免费按摩时认识的
while I was giving free massages outside the U.N.
我不知道他是哪个国家的人
And I don't know where his country is.
先说你为什么要在联合国大楼外做免费按摩
Let's start with the free massages at the U.N.
这是我的新目标  我认为
It's my new thing. I figure,
平和的身体可以缔造和平
"Bodies at peace make peace."
你搞不好会得第一个诺贝尔按摩奖
You might just get the first Nobel Prize in rubbing.
这家伙是哪个国家的人
So what country is this guy from?
里面有个"G"
There's a "g" in there.
这个国家在哪里
Where's that?
在你的地图上
In your atlas!
我没有地图
I don't have an atlas.
不过等等  我有地球仪  等一下
But wait, I do have a globe. Hold on.
菲比  他是什么样的人
So Pheebs, what's this guy like?
他很
Well, he's very...
有冲劲
dashing, you know?
而且非常练达
And very, very sophisticated.
他不会讲英文
And he doesn't speak English...
但他的翻译说  他对我意乱情迷
but according to his translator he totally gets me.
好了  给
Okay, here you go.
这是什么
What is this?
地球仪
It's a globe.
也是削笔刀
And a pencil sharpener.
有什么要复印的吗  我要去影印店
Anybody need anything copied? I'm going down the Xerox place.
不用了  谢谢
No, thanks.
随便给我什么拿去复印就好
Okay, listen, just give me anything I can make two of.
如果你没有东西要复印  干嘛要去
If you don't have anything to copy, why are you go down there?
你又要去看那个
Are you just gonna down there to gawk at that hot girl...
穿了肚脐环的美女吗
with the bellybutton ring again?
没错  要一起去吗
Yeah. You wanna come?
好啊
Yeah!
快  克萝伊  先把你的顾客解决掉
Come on, Chloe. Finish with your customer first.
快点  克萝伊  快点  克萝伊
Come on, Chloe. Come on, Chloe!
要复印吗
Can I help you?
我们对复印的需求有些迟疑
You know what, we're having second thoughts about our copying needs.
还需要时间重新考虑下
And we'll need more time to think about it.
克萝伊  跟我换  有人迷上你了
Chloe, switch with me. There's some guys here's got a crush on you.
好吧  真是伤人
Okay, that hurt us.
你们好  早上以后就没再看见你们了
Hi, guys. I haven't seen you since this morning.
这个嘛
Well...
那个
you know.
你们明天晚上有事吗
What are you guys doing tomorrow night?
我们两个
Both of us?
也许吧  害怕了吗
Maybe. Does that scare you?
别紧张  艾塞克在菲力酒吧当DJ
Relax. Just Isaac's deejaying at The Philly.
-你们也去玩吧  -我们会的
- You should come. - We'll be there.
太好了  到时候见
Great. I'll see you then.
好啊  摇摇摇
All right! Rock on.
他说和你散步让他觉得仿佛
He says that walking with you
这个陌生的城市就是他的家
makes this strange city feel like home.
我也是  虽然这里本来就是我家
Me too. Although this city is my home.
我说的是蠢话  别跟他说我说的这些
So that's dumb, what I said. Don't tell him I said that.
你自己编吧
You make something up.
很好  谢谢
Nice! Thank you.
我家到了
This is me, here.
你的眼睛好美
Your eyes are very pretty.
非常谢谢你
Thank you very much.
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
他想吻你
He would like to kiss you.
你不必麻烦了
You don't have to do that now.
不  我不是说他  是你不必麻烦了
No, no, not him! No, you don't.
时机已经过了
The moment's over.
看  就在这里
See, there it is, right there.
好小
It's small.
对  但赛尔吉说德军花了六星期
Yeah, but Sergei said it took the Germans six weeks...
才横跨国境
to get all the way across it.
-你开心吗  -当然
- So you had fun? - Yeah.
你知道吗  只可惜约会的时候
Except for, you know, when you're on a date...
虽然非常愉快
and you're getting along really great...
但他的翻译碍手碍脚
but the guy's translator keeps getting in the way?
不知道
No.
瑞秋在房间里吗
Is Rach in her room?
她还没下班  但叫你打电话给她
No, she's still at work, but she told me to tell you to call her.
什么  她又要放我鸽子  她怎么可以这样
What? Is she gonna cancel on me again? How could she do this?
她忘记这是我们的周年纪念日了吗
Doesn't she know it's our anniversary?
罗斯  我对这件事只知道这么多
All right, Ross. This is the extent of my knowledge on the subject.
打电话给瑞秋
"Call Rachel."
底下是什么
What's that on the bottom?
是我的涂鸦  戴高顶礼帽的瓢虫
That's my doodle of a ladybug with a top hat.
很漂亮
She's fancy.
喂
Hello?
-嘿  亲爱的  -嗨
- Hey, honey. - Oh, hi.
怎么回事
What's...how's it going?
运货出了大问题  我得把这批货弄到
There was a disaster in shipping. I have to get this order in.
对不起亲爱的  不过看样子
Honey, I'm so sorry, but it looks like
我要开通宵了
I'll be here all night.
什么  那我过去好不好
What? Well, how about I come up there?
不要  亲爱的拜托
No, honey, please.
我要处理的事情太多了
I just have too much to deal with.
反正我今晚要跟塞尔吉约会
Anyway, I'm going out with Sergei again tonight, and....
你能不能当翻译的女伴
Could you come and be the translator's date...
这样我们想独处的时候
so that when we, it's time for our alone time
你们两个可以离开
you two can split off?
他长得挺帅的
You know, he's kind of cute.
你说挺帅的  是真的很帅
Kind of cute like really kind of cute?
还是跟你的朋友  屎屁股赖利一样帅
Or "kind of cute" like your friend Spackle-Back Larry?
别这样叫他
Don't call him that.
他叫做屎屁股哈利
His name is Spackle-Back Harry.
知道吗  也许我们该出发了
You know what? Maybe we should get going.
克萝伊说几点到
I mean what time did Chloe say we should get there?
-十点半  -现在几点
- 10:30. - What time is it now?
四点半
4:30.
我们再坐会儿好了
All right. So we'll hang out.
记得她提过我们三个人那回事吗
Remember when she brought up that thing about the three of us?
记得很清楚
Yes, vividly.
-她是开玩笑的吧  -我想是的
- She was kidding about that, right? - Yeah, I think so.
我想也是
Yeah, I think so.
老天  如果今晚出现这种场面那就太诡异了
God, it'd be weird if that situation presented itself tonight.
对  我是说...
Yeah, I mean...
我们该怎么办
what would we do?
兄弟  我可不知道
Dude, I don't know.
她是开玩笑的
She was kidding.
她是...
She was....
我们应该订下基本规则  以防万一
You know, just in case, maybe we should come up with set ground rules.
对  那当然
Yeah. For sure.
最重要的原则就是  "绝对不要张开眼睛"
Okay. Probably want the first one to be, "Never open your eyes."
你可不想在做什么的时候
Because you don't want to be doing something...
抬头一看  对不对
and then look up, right?
看到你不想看的东西
And see something that you don't want to be seeing.
说得好  不错
Good call. Nice.
等等  等等
Hold it! Hold it!
万一我的眼睛闭上  然后
What if my eyes are closed, and...
我的手在那里...
and my hand is out there....
好吧  眼睛不能闭着
Okay, eyes open at all times!
我们怎么决定
How do we decide where we...
哪个人
you know, each would...
要在
you know...
哪里
be?
对  我们可以丢硬币决定
Right. Well, you know, we could flip for it.
我想也是  不过头尾分别代表什么
I guess. But like, what's heads and what's tails?
如果你连这个都不知道
If you don't know that,
我也不想跟你一起上了
then I don't want to do this with you.
不  订单就在我面前
No, no. I am looking at a purchase order right here...
上面说我们订的是里维拉比基尼
and it clearly states that we ordered the Rivera bikini
各种尺寸和颜色都有
in a variety of sizes and colors and...
这跟我穿什么有何相干
What does it matter what I'm wearing?
可以请你的主管过来吗  谢谢
Could I please speak to your supervisor? Thank you.
等着
We're hold.
我的天  你来干什么
My God! What are you doing here?
你说你不能出去  所以...
Well, you said you couldn't go out, so....
你带了野餐篮  真是个好男朋友
You brought a picnic! What a boyfriend.
就这么定了  星期一我要开始化妆
That's it. On Monday, I start wearing makeup.
罗斯  亲爱的  你很体贴
Ross, honey, this is very nice,
但我现在大难临头
but I've got a crisis.
但我这有蒸麦粉
But I've got couscous!
亲爱的  对不起
Honey, I'm sorry,
我知道今天是我们周年纪念
I know it's our anniversary...
但我在电话里跟你说过  我没有时间停下来
but I told you on the phone, I don't have time to stop.
你不必停下来  我是隐形人  看不到
Okay, you don't have to stop. I'm invisible. I'm not here.
对  可是  我不...
Yeah, but I don't...
是谁批准这批货的
Who approved that order?
我们这里没有马克·罗宾逊
Well, there is no Mark Robinson in this office.
打电话给马克
Get me Mark on the phone!
我喜欢马克  你认识他吗
I love Mark. Do you know Mark?
当然
Yeah.
让我看看手中的订单
Let me just check that with what I've got here.
038不是本店的号码
All right, see, 038 is not the number for this store.
那是亚特兰大的号码
038 is Atlanta.
胡椒
Pepper?
我不用
None for me.
好  对不起
Okay, sorry!
对不起  我刚才说商店号码是错的
I'm sorry. As I was saying, the store number is wrong.
对不起  可是...
And I'm sorry, but
我的天
Oh, my God!
抱歉  我待会儿再打给你
Excuse me, I'm sorry. I'm gonna have to call you back.
有个小丑在这里捣乱
I've got Shemp in my office.
-你这是干嘛  -对不起
- What are you doing? - I'm sorry.
但你电话讲完了  喝杯酒吧
But somebody's off the phone! How about a glass of wine...
围着火对饮  我可以再把火升起来
by the fire? I can get it going again....
罗斯  你没有听我说话  我没空
Ross, you're not listening to me. I don't have time to stop.
得了吧  瑞秋  你连十分钟都没有吗
Come on, Rachel. You don't have what? 10 minutes?
我连十分钟都没有
I don't have 10 minutes!
苏菲  她有十分钟时间吗
Sophie, does she have 10 minutes?
罗斯  我说过没有
Ross. I told you, I don't!
别对我吼  我一个礼拜没见到你了
Don't yell at me, okay? This is the most I've seen you all week.
听好了  我现在没空理你
Look, I cannot do this right now.
我的交货时间快到了
I've got a deadline!
回家去  我们回头再说
Would you just go home and I'll talk to you later.
-可是等一下...  -再见
- Yeah, but wait! - Goodbye!
那个是我们的三孔打孔机
Actually, that's our three-hole punch.
刚才的事
Look, about what happened earlier.
我完全了解  你的压力很大
I completely understand. You were stressed.
我本来要给你机会向我道歉的
I was gonna give you a chance to apologize to me.
凭什么  凭你把我赶出办公室吗
For what. For letting you throw me out of your office?
你没有权利到我办公室来  罗斯
You had no right coming down to my office, Ross.
你不能带着野餐篮到人家的办公室去
You do not bring a picnic basket to somebody's work...
除非那个人是公园管理员
unless maybe they're a park ranger!
原谅我只想在周年纪念日跟女朋友在一起
Excuse me for wanting to be with my girlfriend on our anniversary.
老天  我真是混蛋
Boy, what an ass am I!
但我说过我没有时间
But I told you I didn't have the time!
你一直都没时间
Well, you never have the time.
我觉得自己好像根本没有女朋友  瑞秋
I don't feel like I even have a girlfriend anymore, Rachel.
罗斯  你到底想让我怎么做
Ross, what do you want from me?
你是不是要我辞职
Do you want me to quit my job...
好让你觉得自己有女朋友
so you can feel like you have a girlfriend?
不  我只希望你了解这只是一份工作
No, but it would nice if you'd realize that it's just a job.
-只是一份工作  -没错
- Just a job? - Yes.
罗斯  这是我人生中第一次
Ross, do you realise it's the first time in my life
做我真正喜欢的事
I'm doing something I actually care about!
我这辈子第一次
This's the first time in my life
发挥自己的专长
I'm doing something I'm actually good at!
如果你不了解
If you don't get that...
我了解  我非常了解  也为你高兴
I get that, okay? I get that big time, and I'm happy for you.
但我受够了跟你的答录机谈恋爱
But I'm tired of having a relationship with your answering machine!
我不知道该怎么办
I don't know what to do any more!
我也不知道
Well, neither do I!
这是因为马克吗
Is this about Mark?
我的天
Oh, my God!
好  不是
Okay, it's not.
我的老天爷
Oh, my God!
我不能总跟你为同一件事吵架  罗斯
I cannot keep having this same fight over and over again, Ross.
天哪  你让我受不了
No, you're making this too hard.
我让你受不了  你要我怎么做
I'm making this too hard? Okay, what do you want me to do?
我不知道  我不知道  这样吧
I don't know! I don't know! Look...
也许我们应该分开一下
maybe we should just take a break!
好吧  好吧
Okay, okay.
很好  你说得对  我们冷静一下  好吗
Fine, you're right. Let's take a break. Let's cool off. Okay?
我们去吃冻酸奶吧
Let's get some frozen yogurt or something.
不
No.
我们分开吧
A break from us.
过去五年来在逐页复印方面进步很大
And the advances in collating in the past five years.
我们进了一台X5000
We just got in an X-5000, you know?
有了X5000   X50看起来就像T71
This X-5000 makes an X-50 look like a T-71.
研究恐龙的人来了
It's the dinosaur guy!
-你好  罗斯  -你好  克萝伊
- Hi, Ross! - Hi, Chloe.
介绍你认识我的朋友
I want you to meet some friends of mine.
他是我的偶像
This guy's my hero.
他要把东西放大四倍
He comes in with stuff, he wants it blown up 400%.
我说我们不印  他说非印不可
We say we don't do that. He says, "You gotta."
知道吗  结果我们办到了
You know what? We did it.
现在有人要放大四倍
And now anytime anybody wants 400,
我们就说"罗斯它吧"
we just say, "Let's Ross it!"
而且只有一种颜色
And that's the only color that comes in.
克萝伊  你有硬币吗  我要买安全套
Yo, Chloe! Do you have a quarter for the condom machine?
你怎么会来
So what are you doing here?
今晚不是你的周年纪念日吗
I thought tonight's your big anniversary dinner.
计划略有改变
A little change of plans.
我们打算分手
We're gonna break up instead.
我还会说一点法文
Okay and I can also speak a little French.
怎么了  我说的是什么
Why? What did I say?
你刚才问我  今晚要不要跟你上床
Well, you just asked if I wanted to go to bed with you tonight.
我的天
Oh, my God!
难怪我在莫立斯餐厅得到那么好的服务
No wonder I get such great service at Cafe Maurice.
敲敲敲
Knock, knock, knock.
麻烦你告诉塞尔吉  我很欣赏
Hi. Could you please tell Sergei that I was fascinated...
布特罗斯·布特罗斯-加利
by what Boutros Boutros-Ghali
在《纽约时报》上的文章
said in the New York Times?
你没有说布特罗斯·布特罗斯-加利
You didn't say "Boutros Boutros-Ghali."
布特罗斯·布特罗斯-加利
Boutros Boutros-Ghali.
他说他也是
He says he was too.
有意思
Interesting.
我在想...
So I was wondering
趁你们还没开口说话
Okay, ah, before you get all talky again...
麻烦你告诉塞尔吉
could you also please tell Sergei...
我很喜欢他的西装
that I really like his suit.
他说  "谢谢你  你今晚很美
He said, "Thank you very much. He thinks you look pretty tonight.
你的秀发如阳光般闪闪发亮"
Your hair, golden like the sun."
这么说你是个厨师
So you're a chef?
我打算自己开一间餐厅
I'm also thinking of opening up my own restaurant.
-是嘛  -莫妮卡
- Really? - Monica,
跟你说几句悄悄话好吗
Could I talk to you behind my menu please?
你这是干什么
What are you doing?
我在聊天啊
Well, I was having a conversation.
但米夏对你非常有意思
But Misha's so interested in you,
而塞尔吉跟我根本说不上话
Sergei and I haven't been able to say two words to each other.
你要我安安静静地坐着
You want me to sit silently,
听你们三个人说话吗
while the three of you have conversation?
那就再好不过了  谢谢
That would be great. Thank you.
-你好  -嗨  我是马克
- Hello. - Hi. It's Mark.
怎么  我有口臭吗
What? Is it my breath?
不  对不起  我以为是别人打来的  嗨
No. Sorry. I just thought you were somebody else. Hi.
嗨  我本想打电话留言的
Hi, look, I was just gonna leave a message.
今晚不是你的周年纪念日吗
Isn't tonight your big anniversary dinner?
瑞秋  你没事吧
Rach? Are you okay?
我没事
Yeah, I'm fine.
你想聊聊吗  我可以过来
You wanna talk? I mean I can come over.
真的不必了  没关系
No! Really, no. Please. That's okay.
好  我带中国菜过来
All right. I'm coming over and I'm bringing Chinese food.
我不饿
I'm not hungry.
是我要吃的
It's for me.
好吧  再见
Okay. Bye.
-你打算怎么办  -我能怎么办
- So what're you gonna do? - What can I do?
对方想分手  就只能分手了
One person wants to break up, you break up.
才不是  你们两个非比寻常
No way. This is you guys.
快打电话和好
Call her and work it out.
我们刚刚才大吵一架  不用先等一段时间吗
Come on. We just had this huge fight. Don't I have to wait awhile?
又不是刚吃完饭不能游泳  去打电话
It isn't like swimming after you eat. Pick up the phone!
吃完饭不能游泳完全不可信
You know that swimming thing is a myth.
去跟我蓝尼叔叔说吧
Tell that to my Uncle Lenny.
为什么  他怎么了
Why? What happened to him?
没怎么  他非常相信这回事
Nothing. He just really believes in that.
然后我们大吵了一架  弄得很僵
Then we got into this big stupid fight it was awful.
我说他把我当公园管理员什么的
I told him he treats me like a park ranger, something....
然后
And then...
我告诉他我想分开
I told him I wanted to take a break.
我不想分开
I don't want to take a break.
我真替你难过
I'm sorry.
蛋卷
Egg roll?
不用
No.
然后我打电话给他  他不在家
And then I called him and he wasn't there.
他大概只是出去了
He's probably just out.
谢谢你  你说的话真有用  你来了真好
Thank you, that's very helpful. I'm glad you came over.
喂
Hello?
是我
Hi, it's me.
你打来就好了
Oh, I'm so glad you called.
真的
Really?
我在想这太荒唐了
I've been thinking, this is crazy.
你不觉得我们可以再沟通吗
Don't you think we can work on this?
你想喝什么
What do you want to drink?
那是谁
Who's that?
没有人
Nobody?
我可以把苹果汁喝光吗
Is it okay if I finish the apple juice?
是马克吗
Is that Mark?
亲爱的  他只是过来...
Honey, look, he just came over...
好  我懂了
Yeah, got it!
恐龙先生  看看你好伤心啊
Hey, Dinosaur Guy! Look at you, so sad.
来跳舞吧
Come dance.
没关系  谢谢你
That's okay. Thanks.
你不必笑  只要跳舞就好了
You don't have to smile. You just have to dance.
我不想跳舞  我想喝酒  好吗
I don't feel like dancing. I feel like having a drink, okay?
好的
Okay.
两瓶啤酒
Two beers!
兽医跟我说时候到了
And the vet said it was time.
我在地球的另一端
And so from half a world away...
我母亲把电话拿到它耳朵旁边
while my mother held the phone to his ear...
我用七种语言跟我的狗说再见
I said goodbye to my dog in seven languages...
-给我一张纸巾好吗  -没问题
- Could I have a tissue? - Oh, sure.
希望你不会不小心
I just hope you don't accidentally...
吸进鼻子里呛死
suck it up through your nose and choke on it.
塞尔吉为我今晚的言行道歉
Sergei would like to apologize for my behavior tonight.
跟他说  "我接受他的道歉"
Well, tell him, "Apology accepted."
他真是难以置信  三年来
Oh, he's unbelievable. I mean for the first time in three years
第一次有人想跟我说话
someone actually wants to talk to me,
但你想他会让我这么好过吗  当然不会
But do you think he would let me enjoy that? No!
你这个笨蛋外交官
You silly diplomat.
你怎么不学英文啊  塞尔吉
Why don't you learn some English, Sergei?
对不起  你的晚餐不是他付帐的吗
Excuse me, but isn't he paying for your dinner?
人家的狗刚刚过世了
The man's dog just died.
我辞职了
I have just resigned my post.
你愿不愿意陪我去彩虹厅
Would you care to accompany me to the Rainbow Room?
我有外交官优惠券
I have diplomatic coupons.
这是我的荣幸
It would be my pleasure.
我的男伴有优惠券
My guy has coupons.
你的男伴连"优惠券"都不会讲
Your guy can't even say "coupons".
盘子
Plate.
盘子  对  盘子
Plate! Yes! Plate!
看  我们不需要他们
See, we don't need them.
-盘子  -嗯
- Plate? - Yeah.
我喜欢这首歌
I like this song.
你等于已经在跳舞了
Well, you're practically dancing, already.
-不如到这里来跳吧  -算了
- Why don't you just do it over here? - No, no.
怎么  你结婚了吗
What are you, married?
因为这也无所谓
Because that's okay.
在家...
Oh, be home, be home, be home....
be home, be home, be home....
你不在家
You're not home.
还是不笑
Still no smile?
美国派小姐
Miss American Pie.
美国
Ameri-can.
这种语言很难学
You know, it's a very hard language.
再来一次
Let's do it again.